<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kye &#39;kkshmz&#39; Shimizu</title>
    <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kye &#39;kkshmz&#39; Shimizu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 23:09:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kkshmz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Review during stay in NYC 2018SS</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/blog/18ss-nyc-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 23:09:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/blog/18ss-nyc-pt1/</guid>
      <description>はじめに WIPだから、色々CSSも壊れるし、まだ工事中だよ。 殴り書きフェス いや、先に行っておくと、まとめって書いてあるけど、まとめてないよ  
研究、、、、FUCK FUCK FUCK FUCK
目次  Exhbition まとめ  Design Research 系 IxD 系（あとで） Fashion? met gala?  まとめ (This is America)  &amp;nbsp;
作者について 自分自身は東京うまれ、アメリカのテキサス州育ち、SFC通いっていうのもあって、アイデンテティー自体はアメリカ人でもないし、日本人でもない中間的な存在であったりする。 地元どこって言われると、困るし、かと言ってアメリカは中学校卒業ぐらいまでだったので、完全にカルチャー染まってるかというと微妙。 あと、割とテキサス州だとSXSWの開催土地としてされるオースティンなどが取り上げられますが、そこからちょっと離れた小さなSan Antonioという田舎だったので、NYの都会感はなかなかびっくりでした。
そんなバックグラウンドもあり、いつも日本全体の立場や あ、あといまだにジャポニカ学習帳で漢字練習してるぐらいなので、多めに見てください
&amp;nbsp;
Exhibiton まとめ 今回は時系列で見た展示会順に記述して見た 本来のNYにいく目的ととしては、半分は旅行みたいなのがあるんだけど、もう半分はアメリカにおけるデザイン教育みたいなのをみたいっていう願望があった。僕自身は東京にいる帰国子女っていうのものあって、いつもヨーロッパで、ロンドンで、LAでみたいな感じで海外のデザインの動向について知りたがりみたいな部分がいつもあった。
え、どういう人？みたいに言われると、今はNikeのDesign Directorになった[Eric Hu]()とかはブログ経由でアジア系のデザイナーとして学生にアドバイスをあげてたり、[Memo Atken]()とかもう最近ではすごいMLの作品を出し続けていて、
とくに自分のデザインエンジニアリングみたいな分野においては、Openframeworks だとZach LibermanがNYだし、ml4aのGene KoganがNYだったり、尊敬してるアーティストのKyle McdonaldもNYだった。だからっていうわけではなかったが、NY自体が特別な感じがしてしょうがなかった。
デザインだけでなく、教育っていうフレームワークにおいてはsfpc率いてるTayoon ChoiとかもNYだし、alternative schoolの普及が意外とNYには多い。 自分で確かめたいっていうのもあって、今回いろんな学校の展示会とかイベントに回った。
NYCにおいてのDesign Research系 SVA Design Research NYCに到着した当日に　School of Visual Arts (= SVA)のDesign Research MAの卒論発表会みたいなものに参加した。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slush Asia 2015</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/slushasia2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 01:13:02 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/slushasia2015/</guid>
      <description>Slush Asia is a project that was started in 2015 with the help of Taizo Son and members of Mistletoe, being the first international Slush that was held outside of Finland. Slush is originally an event that brings together entrepreneurs, investors, startups and students together to discuss and collaborate on working towards the future.  Overview of mainstage   
Slush Asia 2015 was held in an outside venue in Odaiba, with the use of &amp;ldquo;White Rock&amp;rdquo; dome shaped tents that gave a certain appeal of &amp;ldquo;exploration&amp;rdquo; that the startups themselves are doing in terms of business  Overview of mainstage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACT Festival Korea</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/actfestival18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 22:47:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/actfestival18/</guid>
      <description>Original work by Rhizomatiks and Ryuichi Sakamoto, I was asked to partake in the update and installation of Sensing Streams for ACT Festival Korea 2018 held in Gwanju, South Korea.
With the theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s festival being, Otherly Space Knowledge , Rhizomatiks was asked to exhibit Sensing Streams for its outlook on radio waves around us that we cannot see, but use everyday.
The installation is reactive to the radio frequencies that are sensed realtime throughout the room , creating a realization of the waves around us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YUIMA NAKAZATO 2121 Exhibition</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/yn2121/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 17:04:27 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/yn2121/</guid>
      <description>Along with the YUIMA NAKAZATO Paris Couture 18SS Fashion show that was exhibited in Paris, I was asked to participate along with members of the Daijiro Mizuno Lab to help exhibit the show pieces at the 2121 Design Sight located in Roppongi, Tokyo.
Not only other fashion designers, but also artists, engineers, and other creators from different backgrounds were invited to help share the vision that the company had, and also to speculate about the future of the fashion industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Whereabouts of Exchange</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/exchangewhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 01:30:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/exchangewhere/</guid>
      <description>This is a project that was created in collaboration with Sonilab and SJQ++. Sonilab is a creative group of producers that aim to give a different perspective to how we interact with music. Being a member of Sonilab, I was in charge of creating the scraping mechanism for the sounds, rearrange them into genres, and also the scraping mechanism for the images for the interactive tablet in the museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YUIMA NAKAZATO 18SS Show</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/yn18ss-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 11:35:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/yn18ss-show/</guid>
      <description>As part of the YUIMA NAKAZATO Paris Couture 18SS, technical research was displayed during the show to display the process of the design and the concept behind the show pieces.
&amp;ldquo;Mobile Factory&amp;rdquo; is a key concept behind the show pieces, speculating on the future of fashion where fashion itself is not limited to the studio of the fashion designer or the factory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yuima Nakazato 18SS Research</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/yn18ss-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 01:12:08 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/yn18ss-research/</guid>
      <description>Being invited by Daijiro Mizuno Lab, I explored the technical possibilities and researched for initial prototypes and creation for the Yuima Nakazato 2018 Spring Summer Paris Couture Fashion Week.
Inital concepts about the collection were traded among our team and the fashion label, creating initial sketches and prototypes that would give some vision on what kind of structure and detail could be made.
Inspirations came from attractors and gravity fields, which held beauty in being simple mathmatical equations that harvested detailed graphical outputs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Driven Art 2017</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/datadrivenart2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 08:07:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/datadrivenart2017/</guid>
      <description>This is a class project done for the Class &amp;ldquo;Data Driven Art&amp;rdquo; by Daito Manabe and Kakehi Yasuaki exploring the inbetweens of brain interface. Other adjucent professors include Shinya Fujii and Masashi Nakatani of the Faculty of Enviornmental Information at Keio University.
  The class itself was a intensive workshop based class that was done throughout the span of a week, with introductions into the current state of OpenBCI and other brain interface mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Tactical Bench</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/urbantactical/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 17:05:24 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/urbantactical/</guid>
      <description>This project was for a Digital Fabrication Class held in the summer of 2017, to fabricate a product that would help people be able to participate in urban tacticalism in Yokohama. We designed a bench and table system using CNC and CAD software that would allow people to create benches and tables from already avaliable structure in Yokohama.
The architecture of the bench is created using a joint mechanism that is able to designed to create universal designs that enable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kochi Kame Theme Park</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/kochikame/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 21:00:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/kochikame/</guid>
      <description>   Toy insects are placed randomly throughout the Tatami, japanese flooring material made out of rice straw, that are then formed to create hidden characters.
Credit:  Creative Director / Programmer : Saito Tatsuya Programmer / Production Assistance : Kye Shimizu Production Management : Bibariki inc.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I wish I knew before I was twenty</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/whentwenty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 15:26:33 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/whentwenty/</guid>
      <description>&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; “I don’t mean you’re all going to be happy. You’ll be unhappy – but in new, exciting and important ways.” – Edwin Land &amp;ldquo;&amp;rsquo;
The big two oh. One thing that I do think now is that I want to make this year, the best year of my life.
It&amp;rsquo;s the last year that I can apply for something like the Founders Fund Foundation for young entrepreneurs, and its something that I have been putting myself to do something for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony IFA 2016</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/sonyifa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 19:38:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/sonyifa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Created the Xperia XZ camera booth for IFA 2016 as part of Abacus Inc, a digital conglomerate headed by Saito Tatsuya. The interactive booth showcased some of the possibilities of the new flagship from Sony.
  3 booths were setup to showcase the features of the camera that came with the flagship smartphone.
The first is the shutter speed of the smartphone, which was displayed by the use of a toy train running along a track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junction Asia</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/junctionasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 15:43:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/junctionasia/</guid>
      <description>Junction Asia was created in a joint program with the Junction in Helsinki, that would partake a week before Slush happened.
  Junction Asia was created with the international audience as well as designers in mind, who would be hesitant to join other hackathons that heavily focused on the use of APIs.
  Through the production of the event, I participated in collaborating with companies through sponsorships, and the production of the venue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slush Asia 2016</title>
      <link>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/slushasia2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 15:42:57 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kkshmz.github.io/projects/slushasia2016/</guid>
      <description>Slush Asia is a project that was started in 2015 with the help of Taizo Son and members of Mistletoe, being the first international Slush that was held outside of Finland. Slush is originally an event that brings together entrepreneurs, investors, startups and students together to discuss and collaborate on working towards the future.  overview of the venue   
Slush Asia 2016 was the first event that respected the ways in which Slush in Finland was organized and run by wholly by approximately 2000 students in Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>